Priyesh Shekhar Ghoradkar

78/5, Western Railway Quarters, Matunga Road, Mumbai - 400019, India

Email: pghoradkar1@student.gsu.edu LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/priyeshg Phone: +91 8451845459

SUMMARY:

A Data Engineering Professional with 4.5 years of experience in IT Consulting and Solutions in Manufacturing and Healthcare industries, aspiring to pursue a Master's degree in Data Science from GSU. I am especially interested in predictive analytics and big data analytics. After completing my education, I want to establish myself as a competent Data Scientist. In the long run, I would like to become a data science architect and make an impactful contribution to the field of data science.

EDUCATION:

Bachelor of Engineering in Instrumentation,

2013 - 2017

Ramrao Adik Institute of Technology (RAIT), Affiliated to Mumbai University, Mumbai, India

CGPA: 7.01/10

RELEVANT COURSES:

Applied Mathematics, Structured Programming Approach, Object-Oriented Programming & Methodology, Industrial Data Communication, and Application Software Practices. Relevant courses in high school: Data Structures, Operating Systems, HTML, C ++ Programming, Microcontrollers, and Networking & Technology.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Eli Lilly & Company, Bengaluru, India Engineer I – Software & Configuration

Jul 2020 - Present

- Currently working as a software engineer on an Analytics and Insights project.
- Responsible for architecting, building, and deploying fault-tolerant and cost-effective data pipelines on the AWS cloud with a test-driven setup.
- For data migration, primarily working on AWS native services like AWS Glue, Amazon Redshift, AWS Lambda, CloudFormation, AWS Kinesis, and API Gateway.
- Developed one of the most innovative and cost-saving processes called the 'Database Bootstrap and Migration Process' to automate the DBA support activity. The suggested process proved to be economically efficient.
- Built on-premise ETL logic in AWS Glue and in Redshift Stored Procedures & Functions.
- Developed a process for on-board data in the S3 Data Lake using the recursive AWS lambda function. **Saved 90% of the data extraction time.**
- Responsible for building BI reports, deriving new understanding from big data, transferring it to actionable items for our business users, interpreting big data, and communicating the data understanding through sophisticated visualization techniques using Tableau.
- Worked on predictive modeling and developed an ML model called JARVIS to predict the winners of IPL matches for the Lilly India IPL tournament. The models used include Decision Tree, Random Forest, XGBoost, LightGBM, and an Ensemble Model. JARVIS's prediction accuracy was 74%.

Tata Consultancy Services, Mumbai, India

System Engineer

Jan 2018 - Jun 2020

- Got trained in the Business Intelligence & Performance Management stream and worked on core skills and concepts like SQL, Python, ETL (Extract, Transform, & Load), data mining, data analytics, data warehousing, and BI tools like Informatica and Tableau.
- Responsible for understanding the data and business requirements, and then building ETL pipelines using Informatica Power Centre. Heavily worked on SQL and with multiple databases and data warehouses like Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redshift, SAP Hana, and Snowflake.
- Also, developed the ETL logic on the cloud using various AWS services. Received several rewards for excellent work on niche technologies like AWS Glue for handling Big Data and delivering it within strict time constraints. Saved 70% of the operating costs after moving the ETL pipeline into AWS.

1. Data Extraction using Recursive AWS Lambda with CI/CD setup

Jul 2021 - Aug 2021

Developed an innovative and cost-effective process to onboard data from any relational database to an AWS S3 bucket using the lambda function in a recursive fashion. Flexibility to fetch data from sources like S3, dynamoDB, APIs, data warehouses, etc.

Link:https://github.com/priyesh009/aws-data-project/tree/master/codes/aws_lambda_codes/recursiveLambda

2. Data Engineering using Apache Airflow

Apr 2021 - May 2021

The project aimed to create a data pipeline that gathers data from different locations at a different frequency and then transforms the data and merges it into a single file. The orchestration was done with the help of airflow, which was running on AWS EC2 and the data transformation was done with the help of Python using the pandas module.

Link: https://github.com/priyesh009/aws-data-project/tree/master/Airflow_Project

3. Data Science Projects

Jul 2021 - Present

The below GitHub link contains some small-scale data science projects.

Link: https://github.com/priyesh009/ds-projects

SKILLS

- **Technologies:** Python, SQL, Java, AWS, Azure, Apache Spark, Apache Airflow, and Machine Learning.
- Tools: Tableau, AWS Glue, AWS Lambda, AWS CloudFormation, Amazon Redshift, S3, Snowflake, Informatica PowerCenter, Postgres, MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server, and Continuous Integration & Continuous Deployment using AWS Developer Tools.
- **Methodologies:** Exploratory Data Analysis, Predictive Modeling, Big Data Engineering, Data Visualization, Data Migration, Data Mining, Data Modeling, Data Warehousing, Classification, Clustering, and Regression.

TECHNICAL CERTIFICATIONS:

- AWS Certified Data Analytics Specialty, Score 83%, 2021.
- AWS Certified Developer Associate, Score 92%, 2021.
- AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate, Score 81%, 2020.
- Certified Scaled Agile Framework 5 Practitioner, 2020.
- Udemy: Tableau, Airflow, Informatica, and Snowflake, 2020.
- Python for Data Science, 2019.
- Oracle Certified Professional Java Programmer, Score 100%, 2017.
- Presented technical paper on "Active RF based Student tracking system" which was approved by Indian Society of Technical Education (ISTE) at National level Student conference, 2017.

ACTIVITIES AND AWARDS:

- Inspire points reward for setting up a cost-effective data ingestion process in AWS, Eli Lilly & Co., 2021.
- Hackerrank SQL and Python Badges, Hackerrank, 2021.
- RISE Award for stunning performance in the Tableau Reporting Project, Eli Lilly & Co., 2021.
- Member of AWS Community Builder, an exclusive program managed by AWS. Here, I got a chance to share some innovative techniques for collecting data from various data sources with one of the most cost-effective techniques at the community level. Amazon web services, 2021.
- Inspire points reward from LillyUSA stakeholders for setting up cost-effective database bootstrap and migration processes in AWS, which is saving thousands of dollars for the project, Eli Lilly & Co, 2020.
- Certificate for playing a role at Toastmasters International Speech Competition, Toastmaster International, 2019
- Start Team award for working round the clock on multiple ETL developments & delivering them within strict time constraints before the production freeze, TCS, 2019.
- Won best business skill Team Award for successfully conducting an event LINGUA FRANCA, TCS, 2018.

